# Dr. Víctor Ponce López



#### Contact

vponcelop<at>gmail.com vponcelo.github.io London, United Kingdom

#### Languages

Catalan \*\*\*\*\*(native),
Spanish \*\*\*\*\*(native),
English \*\*\*\*\*(fluent),
Français \*\*\*\*\*
(basic reading/writing/oral).

#### Programming Languages, Libs, Tools, Web and Environments

Python, MATLAB, C++/C#/C, R, PyCharm, Netbeans, Eclipse, VS/VC++, SVN/GIT, Redmine, ĽTEX, XML, PostgreSQL, SQL, MySQL, Tableau, Hive, Spark, Hadoop, CodaLab, Kaggle, Bash, PHP/HTML/CSS/JavaScript;

# Deep Learning & Computer

Vision libraries and toolboxes:

Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras,
GAN, CNN, LSTM, dlib,
CUDA+CuDNN, Kinect™SDK,
open{CV/NI/GL}, CNTK+;
evolutionary computation and
statistical pattern recognition:

numpy, matplotlib, sklearn,

optimtool, gatool, pmtk3, deap, pandas, statsmodel.

### **OS Preferences**

GNU/Linux \*\*\*\*
Windows \*\*\*\*
MacOS \*\*\*\*
Android \*\*\*\*
iOS \*\*\*\*

## **short** bio

I am a former Research Fellow at the UCL Energy Institute. I am a member of the European Laboratory for Learning and Intelligent Systems (ELLIS) and a Honorary Research Fellow at the Dept. of Computer Science at the University of Bristol. I was a Research Scientist in Eurecat at the Big Data Analytics Unit. I hold a PhD at the Dept. of Mathematics and Computer Science, University of Barcelona (UB). I received my B.Sc. degree in Computer Science and Engineering at the Faculty of Mathematics of UB, and my M.Sc. degree in Artificial Intelligence at the Polytechnic University of Catalonia. I was affiliated to the Computer Vision Center and the Open University of Catalonia, in the groups HuPBA and SUNAI; and the group Qarma at the Laboratoire d'Informatique Fondamentalle, Aix-Marseille Université.

# **experience**

2020-2022 University College London

London, United Kingdom

Research Fellow in Machine Learning at the UCL Energy Institute

- Natural Language Processing on Disasters for the Environment & Energy.
- Time-Series Forecasting of Energy Markets using Deep Neural Networks.

2017–2020 University of Bristol

Bristol, United Kingdom

PostDoc Research Associate & Research Fellow at the Visual Information Lab.

- Time-Series Prediction of Seasonal Ground Surface Deformation.
- · Computer Vision for Human Activity Recognition in Home Healthcare.
- Domain Adaptation, Self-Supervised Learning, GANs, Person Re-IDentification.

past-2017 Eurecat Technology Center of Catalonia, University of Barcelona, Open University of Catalonia, Computer Vision Center, Dept. of Justice @ GOV of Catalonia, and Barcelona City Council's Dept. of Education, Culture and Welfare

Research Scientist, PostDoc, Collaborations in Research & IT, international PhD stay, 40+ scientific publications and peer-reviews, teaching and material preparation, organization/attendance on international conferences, events, and seminars.

- 4 impact factor journals, 17 conference proceedings, and 1 book chapter.
- ChaLearn Looking At People collaboration with Microsoft, NVIDIA, Google, Amazon, Disney, Facebook, Orange, MWC-GSMA.
- · Research projects on human behavior analysis within real-world domains.

## education

2012-2016 Ph.D. in Mathematics and Computer Science

Faculty of Mathematics, University of Barcelona

Dissertation: "Evolutionary Bags of Space-Time Features for Human Analysis." Cum

Laude and International Mention.

2010-2012 M.Sc in Artificial Intelligence

Polytechnic University of Catalonia, University of Barcelona, and Rovira i Virgili University.

Dissertation: "Multi-Modal Human Gesture Recognition combining Dynamic Program-

ming and Probabilistic Methods." With Honors.

2006–2010 B.Sc in Computer Science: Systems engineering

Faculty of Mathematics, University of Barcelona.

Dissertation: "Analysis of Oral and Gestural Expression using an Artificial Vision Sys-

tem." With Honors.

### extracurricular

2006-Present **Driving license** 

1998–2004 Musical language and Piano licenses

### interests

I'm a passionate of diversity in research & technology. My main interests are machine learning and deep pattern recognition to address real-world applications. I follow cutting-edge research and technology to be aware of future trends to come and new social needs for the people.